[Music]
hi everyone this is Ravi welcome to
price and tasa automation tutorial as
you all know I've already published 38
YouTube videos covering different
concepts of TSA
automation this is our lesson 39 in
terms of overall task automation
Concepts and this is our lesson
24 in terms of advanced level Concepts
so in this lesson I'm going to teach you
more string operations this is our part
two of string operation so here I'm
going to teach you how can you convert
the string from lowercase to uppercase
and how can you convert the string from
uppercase to lower case and also I'm
going to teach you how can you perform
number of occurrences operations while
automating you web application and I'm
also going to teach you how can you
perform string length operation by using
trient
Tas so let us first understand what is
string to lower so string to lower is an
operation which converts uppercase
characters in The String to the lower
case
characters and the next string operation
is string to Upper which converts lower
case characters in The String to
uppercase
characters and the next operation is
number of
occurrences so this operation counts all
occurrences of the defined input or
pattern in the
string and string length it counts the
number number of characters in The
String so now let us jump onto the
system and see how can we perform these
operations by using trien
tosa so now let us first create a folder
I'm going to create a folder called
string operations part two let me copy
this folder
name and then paste it here and rename
this as part two and then I'm going to
create one
test case called
string
operation okay so first I'm going to
call
one module I'm going to add one module
called set tbox buffer okay set buffer
I'm going to call tbox set buffer and
here I'm going to specify a buffer
value let's say let's take a
string to test this is my buffer name
what is the string that I want to test
is
prentis
tasa automation okay prentis tasa
Automation and here
now I want to First calculate the length
of the string okay what I'm going to do
I'm going to use another called length
Okay this is my buffer I'm defining the
buffer called length
here I want to use this string to buffer
value I'm storing this tent Tas
automation string to a buffer called
string
to test correct so now I want to
use a string length operation so if you
see this is the string length operation
right right
and here I want to calculate the string
length of what
of
buffer this one close Square braces
close curly braces Square braces and
curly braces let's see if this is
correct yeah this is correct what I'm
doing I'm using string length because I
have stored the string called trient
toask automation into your buffer string
to test and now I want to see the length
of this buffer value string length
buffer string to length right so let me
quickly run this and see if it works
okay first let me run this and see if it
works okay
run so let's go here and see if it
calculates the length of the string
yes 26 that's correct it's calculating
the length of the string okay including
the spaces okay and then what is our
next one next one is I'll do one thing
I'm going to do upper
case upper
case so here I'm going to use string to
upper case curly
braces
string to upper case see here string to
Upper now again pass your
buffer same buffer string to
test close and
close that's
it yes so now it should convert this
entire text into a uppercase so now let
me create another buffer I'm going to
store another buffer called
lowercase and here again let's call the
string operation string to lower right
this is string to lower and
here again I'm going to call the buffer
same
buffer
here think we are missing okay here
yes so done
now after lower case I want to
cover uh number of occurrences what I'm
going to
do I'm going
to create
another buffer called number of
occurrences here let me call a new
operation called number of occur
occurrences number of occurrences of
what
of buffer same
buffer
okay but what is the pattern that you
want to see let's say I want to see the
pattern of T so the numeric portion
called T how many times it
is occurring so basically the t is
occurred how many times in this
particular string so here close Square
braces now I need to specify
P close curly braces so what what does
it mean I am asking Tsar
to calculate the number of occurrences
of
T in the value string to buffer that
means this one number of occurrences so
now let us run
this particular test case and see what
happens okay right click and
run so now see the results okay first
tricentis tasa automation is
of length
26 and see here tricentis tasa is
converted to
uppercase and then then the tricentis
tasa is converted to lower case and then
T how many times it is occurring only
three times if you see 1 2 3 4 5 I see
five times but we have specified the
lower case if you see in this tasa we
specified the lower case of T that's why
it is calculating over only lower case
1 2 3 correct so now now if I want to
consider I don't want to consider the
case simply you can ignore the case here
open fa Braes close Square Braes and
here specify it as
ignore case so what it will do now it
calculates the number of T's either it
might be capital T or small T right so
let me run this again and see now it
should come as instead of three it
should give
five so here let's go
here and expand
this number of occurrences if you see
five
occurrences correct Capital 2 and small
T is
three
right so hope you all understand how can
you perform the different string of
operations by using trienes Taska if you
have any queries leave your queries in
the comment box I'll try to respond to
your
queries so you all understand the
concepts of different string operations
that we cover as part of part two please
do subscribe to the channel click on
Bell icon you'll receive notifications
whenever I publish more videos thank
you
[Music]